# JAIMIK M PATEL

# PYTHON DEVELOPER

+91-9773184218

jaimikpatel248@gmail.com

**Vadodara** 

#### **PROFILE**

More than 7 years of experience as Python Developer, Web/Application Developer, System Administrator and Technical Support Executive. Coding with analytical programming using Python, Django and Machine Learning. To serve the organisation with the best of my technical skills and abilities by utilising my educational and professional knowledge and competencies acquired by me in my academic career and professional experience

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Frameworks: Django, Flask and DRF
- **Python Libraries**: Selenium, numpy, pandas, pdfplumber, pyodbc and few more.
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Angular
- **Programming Languages:** Python and Java Script.
- Version Control: Git, GitHub.
- **Cloud Computing:** AWS EC2, S3, Lambda, IAM, AMI, ELB, SQS, SNS, Azure blob, VM, Logic App, container.
- **Application servers:** Apache Tomcat, Nginix, GUnicorn.
- Databases: SQLite3, PostgraySQL, My SQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, HubDB
- **DevOps**: Docker, Jenkins
- Other: Vagrant, Digital Ocean, GUnicorn, Ngiox, Celery and RabbitMQ
- **CRM**: Hubspot
- **CMS**: Django CMS and Wagtail CMS.

## **PROJECTS**

http://dashboard.southcentralus.cloudapp.azure.com

https://www.insynchcs.com/university/webinars

Build a User Authentication Web Application (**Python, Django and Bootstrap**)

Build a Portfolio Project (**Django and PostgraySQL**)

Build Real Estate Project web project (**Django, Bootstrap and SQLite**)

Build a Face Recognition Based Attendance System (Python, Tkinter and OpenCV)

Build a Product Hunt Project (**Django, Bootstrap, SQLite**)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Python Developer, Stemmons Business Pvt Ltd; Vadodara, India — May 2020 - Present I am responsible for Python automation Bot. Which is regularly scrap the data from our business website and push that data to MSSQL, Box, Share-point and TM1 Cognos. I am also responsible for web development as per client need. For that I am using Django, Flaks and Angular.

# Python Developer, InSync HCS; Vadodara, India — April 2019 - April 2020

I am responsible for Python development for in house development. So far I done some web base application and some other projects as well. I also used HubSpot CRM for HubSpot Development. Completed Face Recognition based attendance system with Python, OpenCv and Tkinter libraries.

## Python Developer, Stypix; Ahmedabad, India — Oct 2018 - March 2019

I was responsible for Django development for custom database models and front end development. I was using HTML, CSS, jquery and Bootstrap with Django. Apart from web development published one Amazon Alexa skill, with AWS Lambda and Python development. This skill fetch the dynamic data from our CSV files and give a live output as a voice.

System Admin, Dev IT; Ahmedabad, India — June 2017 - Sep 2018

System Admin, 3ML Services; Auckland, New Zealand — Feb 2014 - May 2017

#### **EDUCATION**

Rajasthan Technical University, Udaipur, India - Computer Science & Engineering, 2013

Tasman International Academies, Auckland, New Zealand - IT Support and Operation, 2016

Gujarat University, Gandhinagar- Bachelor of Legislative Law - 2020

# **Leisure Activity**

Travelling, Reading, Driving, Video games and Movies

#### Reference

Professional reference will be available upon request.